SAI TEJA

User Interface Developer

Email: saitejau12@gmail.com

Phone: (+91) 8977700844

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY:

Versatile **Front-end Developer** with 4+ years of good experience in developing and dedicated to creating optimizing interactive, **user-friendly**, feature-rich **websites** and **web applications**. Leverage UI skills and strong attention to detail in order to deliver original and efficient web solutions. Provide technical knowledge and expertise to build new **websites** from start to finish, and successfully manage a team of other junior software professionals.

RESPONSIBILITIES:

- Translate graphic visual and interactive designs into the presentation layer for highly interactive web applications using responsive design and development techniques.
- Expert experience in HTML5/CSS and building web, responsive/adaptive applications.
- Extensive hands on coding expertise in HTML 5, CSS 3, JavaScript, jQuery and Angular.
- Deep understanding of responsive libraries such as **Bootstrap** and **Foundation by ZURB.**
- Strong understanding of client-side scripting JavaScript libraries and frameworks.
- As a front end developer worked on web applications to access **JSON** and **Rest-full** web services from consumer side by using **JavaScript** and **Angular**.
- Demonstrable success in improving the **user experience** for web applications.
- Good experience in developing/testing websites on multiple browsers and mobile device browsers.
- To increase the usability of application maintains the **consistency** in design and navigational flow.
- Unit testing on web applications with cross browser comparability checking for all trending devices.
- Familiarity with technical considerations when designing for dynamic AJAX-based Web applications.
- Good experience in implementing Continuous Delivery for front end applications.
- Creating and maintaining documentation for development code and technical related topics.
- Performing research on latest trends in the UI development space and implemented best practices.
- Working with Business Analysts and Project Managers to develop proof of concepts.
- Problem-solving skills with the ability to quickly process complex information and present it clearly.
- Worked with the product owners, solution architects and other team members to understand customer requirements and propose for technical solutions.

SKILLS AND EXPERTISE:

Web Technologies

HTML/HTML5 CSS/CSS3 JavaScript JQuery

Frameworks

Angular 2+
Bootstrap V3 & V4
Angular Material
MD Bootstrap
Atomic Design

Development Tools

Visual Studio Atom by Github puTTy New Relic (APM)

Git Based Repository Management

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE:

Genpact India Pvt Ltd, Hyderabad, India

UI/UX Developer

05/2018 – present

- Web application development by using Angular framework along with new standard web technologies.
- Find out the bugs and performance issues and resolved with latest ES6 JavaScript methodologies.
- As a UI developer implemented new web technologies and their advantages that how transform usability of application performance to end user.
- Enhancements type of development is done for informational websites of **GE**.
- Created multiple web responsive pages for CMS applications like word press and Drupal related projects.
- Migrating legacy web application to new standardize web application development process for GE.

TekFriday Processing Solutions Pvt Ltd, Hyderabad, India

UI Developer

06/2017 - 05/2018

- As a UI Developer adopting the new web frame works to develop new user experience web applications.
- End to end web application development and step by step segmentation development done for FAST&UP.
- Maintain the design consistency as per the dynamic data through server to front end.
- Collaborate with Back-end Developers to increase the usability of design.
- Inspiring the creative team and insuring that all are kept-up-to- date with new methods and technologies.
- Providing user friendly designs for brand new applications in internal websites of tekfriday.

iPowerFour Technologies Pvt Ltd, Hyderabad, India

Content Developer

03/2016 - 06/2017

- Worked on daily based modifications in health related informational site with maintenance.
- Front-end curd operations and maintaining the data through API's in web application.
- Developed my first web application and admin dashboard by using angular js.
- Modernizing the sites as per the latest standards.
- Bug fixing and collaborates with team members and developed wire-frames as per client requirements.
- Worked on Non Responsive web pages to Responsive web pages and also tested in multi supported devices.

PROJECTS:

- GE Power, GE Research, GE Digital, GE Renewable Energy
- GE Global Shipper Association Application
- IDM http://www.idmod.org
- FAST&UP https://www.fastandup.in
- SuccessLynk https://www.successlynk.com
- Flex Salary https://www.flexsalary.com
- Rentdelite https://www.rentdelite.com
- Kaiser Permanente https://healthy.kaiserpermanente.org

EDUCATION:

Computer Science and Engineering

Samskruti College of engineering and technology, Hyderabad, India 06/2011 – 09/2015

CERTIFICATES:

- Certified Scrum Master Genpact India Pvt Ltd 10/2018
- Innovation and Creativity Genpact India Pvt Ltd Harvard Manage Mentor by Genpact India Pvt Ltd 03/2019

AWARDS & RECOGNIZATION:

- Sliver Badge Dedicated to time lines for product development.
 Honor Issuer Senior Project manager at Genpact 05/2019
- Sliver Badge Supporting other teams on user interface development.
 Honor Issuer Senior Vice President at Genpact
 10/2018

OPEN SOURCE:

 Github – Contribution to open source projects in java script, Angular, and jQuery https://github.com/TejaNethas

LANGUAGES:

- English
- Hindi
- Telugu

PORTFOLIO:

Here I am including my user interface development experience details in this portfolio website: http://tejanethas.me

DELARATION:

I hereby declare that all the information furnished above is true to the best of my knowledge and belief.

U.SAI TEJA (http://tejanethas.me)